A lot is happening in social, on blogs,
社交媒体、博客、
and around the web at large,
以及庞大的网络上随时都在发生各种事情
and that information is incredibly valuable.
由此产生的信息是非常宝贵的
Social and web monitoring tools come in to
社交和网络监测工具可以帮助
help you understand all sorts of interesting data sets.
抓取各式各样的有趣的数据
For example, you can understand the number of mentions that your brand has.
比如 你可以知道你的品牌的曝光次数
You can take and look at this data and qualify it by time period,
你也可以根据时段、
by segment, and even message penetration.
细分市场、甚至信息渗透 来进一步研究
For example, if you're running a particular campaign,
比如 你正在举办一场特别的营销活动
you might understand how far that campaign had reach.
你想了解这个活动的散播程度
So you may have a particular hashtag that you've attached to this campaign,
你可以设计一个活动特有的主题 用 # 来标记 比如 #MeToo
and now you can see how many mentions this has gathered all around the web.
然后你可以看这个 # 在全网有多少次被提及
You can also identify the locations of
你也可以看看这些对话的地址信息
these conversations and where they're most concentrated.
看看哪里最集中讨论了这个主题
There are even ways to use these tools to identify
这些工具甚至可以用来区分
the types of conversations happening around your brand.
关于你的品牌的讨论的类别
You can take this data,
你可以根据收集到的数据
and without having to look at every conversation,
评估出这些讨论的情感态度
evaluate the sentiment around those conversations.
而不用亲自每一个讨论都去看
Is it primarily positive?
这些讨论主要是正向的？
or primarily negative?
还是负面的？
Or is it just neutral?
还是情感中立？
You can also look at word clouds to understand whether people are talking about
你可以根据词云图 来了解人们在讨论
a particular product or service that you offer more so than anything else.
你的某个特定产品或者服务时 都用了哪些关键词
There are also ways to look at what influencers are participating in
同时也有办法来评估有哪些意见领袖参与了这些讨论
these conversations or how influential that people talking about you are.
或者人们普遍认为你的品牌的影响力有多大
There's also data on what publications are writing about you,
工具也可以提供关于哪些杂志、报社等报道了你的品牌的信息
and within that you can see the specific journalists or bloggers
你可以看到报道记者或者博客主的信息
and even the trends and themes about those particular journalists.
甚至关于这些记者、博主的一些特征信息
You can see what topics they tend to write about or
你会知道他们倾向于写哪类文章
where they typically spend their time around the web.
他们通常都在网上花时间浏览哪些内容
There's also ways to use these tools to identify trending topics.
这些工具也可以用来锁定时下流行的话题
This way you can attach yourself to conversations that are
这样 如果话题与你的品牌可以关联
happening around the web as they make sense to your brand.
你就可以追热点了
There's also ways to organize your customer information.
这些工具也可以用来组织客户信息
You can gain insights about individual segments,
你可以收获到关于客户群体的很多宝贵信息
and see what their likes and interests are to help you better tailor your messaging.
他们的喜好、爱好 让你可以进一步定制营销手段
You also have a way to identify thought leaders and influencers so you can reach out and
也可以用来锁定一些意见领袖或者影响者
start thinking about how they can participate in
这样你可以考虑如何与他们合作
campaigns that you might be deciding to run.
让他们参与到你开展的营销活动里
We can also gather aggregate insights from all of the major platforms.
我们也可以把各个主渠道收集到的洞察聚合起来
So you'll have your native data from Twitter,
比如你有来自 Twitter、
Instagram, YouTube, and Facebook for example.
Instagram、YouTube、 Facebook 的原始数据
So you can use a tool like HootSuite or Sprout Social to help aggregate
你可以使用 HootSuite 或者 Sprout Social 等工具来帮助聚合
those metrics for your channel efforts and see
各个渠道的指标
what's going on across each of those platforms.
然后全局观测每个渠道的表现
Now, you can also use this data for both retroactive insights and proactive insights.
你可以用这些数据来发现对于过去的洞察 或者 对于当前的指导意义
You can look at what happened and figure out why,
你可以看看过去都发生了些什么 以及为什么
or you can start thinking about where to take the brand
或者你也可以根据全网正在发生的讨论
based on the share of conversations that are happening around the web.
决定你的品牌何去何从
Now, these insights can be passed through
你可以利用之前讲过的框架 来进一步落实这些洞察
the same frameworks that we've evaluated to help us identify action.
然后制定行动计划
Let's talk about some popular tools.
现在 介绍下一些常用工具
One of the more high-end tools that you can look at is Sales Force Marketing Cloud.
在高端产品系列 值得推荐的是 Sales Force Marketing Cloud
Now, there are many individual products within
它其实是一系列产品
the marketing cloud such as Social Studio and Data Studio.
包括 Social Studio 和 Data Studio 等
Here you have access to monitoring and brand visibility as well as
通过这套工具 你可以获得关于品牌曝光度的各种数据
features that can extend that data into your initiatives around paid marketing.
你也可以用它来分析各类付费营销项目
This is a fairly market leading product,
这是市场领先产品
but it's also fairly expensive.
但费用也很昂贵
Moving on, there's HootSuite.
接下来是 HootSuite
HootSuite is a social relationship software.
这是一个社交媒体管理平台
It started as a way to automate posts across multiple platforms,
最初 这个平台是帮助客户跨渠道自动发送推文
and now it's evolved to help you execute
现在 它已经升级到可以帮助你在多个渠道
your marketing campaigns across multiple channels.
执行推广活动
It'll have dashboards with all summary metrics
它的数据面板 可以提供所有的总结性指标表现
to give you the tools to track trends in the industry,
让你可以对行业的趋势了如指掌
as well as measure what's going on with your specific campaigns.
同时也清楚你自己的推广活动的情况
Now, this tool tends to be favored by brands that do
如果品牌利用社交渠道做很多客户推广
a lot of customer service via their social channels.
这个平台是他们的至爱
Now, Sysomos is a unified insights driven
Sysomos 是一个集合社交媒体平台
social platform that gives you a way to look at search across many areas.
提供全面的社交媒体数据和工具
Here you can discover, listen, publish, engage,
你可以针对付费和自有媒体来发现、倾听、发布、分析、
and analyze all of the data across both your earned and owned media.
以及有意义的互动参与
This tool has a lot in it.
这个工具非常强大
You can measure mentions of your brand,
你可以看到品牌曝光次数
your competitors or what's going on at
你的竞争品牌的曝光次数
your industry as a whole or it'll allow you to set up
整体行业趋势 如果你对数据有疑问
complex queries for all of
尤其是那些较少关注的用户情况
these less obvious use cases on things that you might want to ask of the data sets.
也可以自定义很复杂的数据查询
Now, Sysomos does bring in data from Twitter and
Sysomos 会从 Twitter、博客、
all of the majority of mentions coming from blogs,
新闻渠道、社交媒体渠道等
news channels, and social channels.
抓取大部分数据和曝光度
Now, a lot of these tools, Sysomos included,
大多数工具 包括 Sysomos
are only going to capture a small percentage of data from Facebook,
只能从 Facebook 获取一小部分数据
and that's because not all Facebook data is publicly available,
这是因为不是所有的 Facebook 数据都是公开的
and this quality will be the same across most tools.
这个限制几乎适用于大部分工具
Now, Awario is another popular tool that makes
Awario 是另一款工具 价廉物美
social media and web monitoring affordable for businesses of just about any size.
几乎所有公司 不论大小 都能用它来做社交媒体和网络监测
It starts at around $29 a month,
最低级套餐只需要 29 美元/月
and they have a lot of capabilities that you'd find an enterprise level tools.
而它的性能几乎可以匹配一个企业型应用
This is a great place to start for a smaller business.
对于小型企业 非常友好
As with any marketing project,
对于任何一个营销推广活动
you need to evaluate the tool that fits your requirement,
你都要选择符合要求的工具
but I think it's really valuable.
但我认为很值得
If you take the time to visit the websites of
如果你能花时间去浏览这些工具的网站
these various tools and explore their features in more depth.
深度挖掘各个工具的性能
Whether you're going to use the tool or not,
不管你是否最终选择了它
you'll gain a deeper awareness of the reach that these tools have,
你都能对这些工具的用处有个更深的了解
and you'll start being able to think creatively about the types of
同时 你也会开始创意性地思考 00:05:25,639 --&gt; 00:00:00,000 可以抓取到哪些数据 并基于此 做出某些决定